JESSICA

resumesample@example

(555) 432-1000.

Montgomery Street, San Francisco, CA 94105

-

8

• : A

•

P

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Dedicated and energetic Registered Dental Hygienist with 3 years of experience as a Dental Hygienist and 10 years of experience as a Dental Assistant. Reliable and motivated team player focused on patient comfort, treatment and preventative care

LICENSES

Registered Dental Hygienist, Indiana, May, 2015 Licensed to Administer Local Anesthesia, Indiana, May 2015 Registered Dental Hygienist, Arizona, June, 2012

Licensed to Administer Local Anesthesia, Arizona, Decembe

American Heart Association, CPR/AED Certified, Renewal M 2017

Certified in Basic Tobacco Intervention Skills, September Certified within the World Cli Laser Institute, May, 2011

SKILL **HIGHLIGHTS**

- Develop a rapport with pat
- Implement treatment base patient needs
- Patient educator
- Trained in traditional, digit phosphor plate x-ray techn
- Familiar with Eaglesoft and Dentrix software
- Professional and hard work team player

EDUCATION

Mohave Community College Bullhead City, Arizona • 2012

Associate of Applied Science: Dental Hygiene - GPA: Dean's List Fall 2010, 2011

Concorde Career College Garden Grove, California • 2000 –

License: Dental Assistant - GPA:

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Tend - Dental Hygienist

New York, NY, · · 09/2013 - Current

- · Perform patient assessments including: medical history; vital signs; extraoral and intraoral examinations; dental charting; periodontal charting
- Expose and evaluate x-rays
- Develop treatment plan with the doctor based on assessments and patient's needs
- Perform adult prophylaxis, child prophylaxis with fluoride treatment, full mouth debridement and scaling and root debridement procedures
- Administer local anesthesia to patients receiving periodontal treatment
- Administer nitrous oxide sedation and Oraqix anesthesia as needed to complete treatment
- Sealant placement
- Place Arestin
- Document all assessments, treatment provided and conversations regarding patient care
- Educate patients on the importance of oral health and provide oral hygiene instructions
- Post operative phone calls following scaling and root debridement procedures
- Assist in sterilization and infection control
- Manage inventory for dental hygiene supplies
- Assist in answering phone calls
- File patients charts

Tend - Dental Hygienist
Atlanta, GA, • • 06/2012 - 09/2013

- Performed patient assessments including: medical history; vital signs; extraoral and intraoral examinations; dental chart; periodontal chart.
- Exposed and evaluated x-rays
- Developed treatment plans with the doctor based on assessments and patient's needs
- Performed adult prophylaxis, child prophylaxis with fluoride treatment, full mouth debridement and scaling and root debridement procedures
- Administered local anesthesia to patients that received periodontal treatment
- Administered nitrous oxide sedation and Oraqix anesthesia as needed to complete treatment
- Sealant placement
- Placed Arestin
- Documented all assessments, treatment provided and conversations regarding patient care
- Educated patients on the importance of oral health and provided oral hygiene
- Scheduled patient appointments and kept a record of recall appointments
- Post operative phone calls following scaling and root debridement procedures
- Assisted on sterilization and infection control

Pacific Medical Centers - Dental Hygiene Student

Eugene, OR, • • 07/2010 - 04/2012

- Performed patient assessments including: medical history; vital signs; extraoral and intraoral examinations; dental charting; periodontal chart.
- Exposed and evaluated x-rays.
- Developed treatment plans based on assessments and patient's needs.
- Performed adult prophylaxis, child prophylaxis with fluoride treatment, full mouth debridement and scaling and root debridement procedures
- · Administered local anesthesia and nitrous oxide sedation
- Placed sealants
- Placed Arestin and performed gingival curettage
- Documented all assessments, treatment provided and conversations regarding patient care
- Educated patients on the importance of oral health and provided oral hygiene instructions
- Scheduled patient appointments and kept a record of recall frequency

- · Post operative phone calls following scaling and root debridement procedures
- · Assisted in sterilization and infection control

Pacific Medical Centers - Dental Assistant

Gardena, CA, • • 09/2007 - 07/2010

- · Assisted doctor during dental treatment and procedures
- Exposed and developed x-rays
- · Responsible for infection control and sterilization
- Ordered and stocked supplies
- Performed Zoom Bleach procedure and created bleach trays for patients
- Responsible for training new employees
- Documented and presented treatment plans
- Documented patient assessments, treatment provided and conversations between the doctor and patient regarding patient care

Pacific Medical Centers - Dental Assistant

Mercer Island, WA, • • 2007 - 09/2007

- Assisted doctor during dental procedures
- · Exposed and developed x-rays
- · Responsible for infection control and sterilization
- Ordered and stocked supplies.
- Performed Zoom Bleach procedure and created bleach trays for patients
- Documented patient assessments and treatment plans

Eric Swainston, D.D.S - Dental Assistant

City, STATE, • • 08/2000 - 05/2006

- · Assisted doctor during dental procedures
- · Exposed and developed x-rays
- · Coronal polished children's teeth
- Responsible for infection control and sterilization
- Ordered and stocked supplies
- Kept track of ingoing and outgoing laboratory cases
- Documented and presented treatment plans
- Documented all assessments, treatment provided and conversations between the doctor and patients regarding patient care
- Answered phone calls and scheduled appointments for patients
- Responsible for billing and collections

COMMUNITY SERVICE

Buckskin 5K Race- Raises money for youth in Parker, Arizona Relay for Life- Raises money for cancer research Give Kids a Smile Day- Provide preventative treatment for children in need Sealant Program- Provide sealants at local schools for children in need Volunteer time at children's schools- Grade papers for teachers Volunteer at children's sports activities- Team mom duties

SKILLS

Dental Hygienist Anesthesia Charting X-rays CPR Infection control Oral hygiene Rapport Scaling Team player Treatment plans